WILLIAM WELCH

SAP Business Analyst - integrating solutions to make a positive impact on the ROI

\$\Lambda +1-159-625-8663 @ elonmusk@fakemail.com
∂ linkedin.com/in/willwelch156 \$\Pi\$ Little Rock, AR

SUMMARY

SAP Business Analyst with 8+ years of experience in integrating, customizing, and maintaining the range of SAP products to suit business needs. Highly apt at systematizing and analyzing business data to predict the best possible outcome. 2021 was the most successful financial year for Carroll due to the integrated SAP solutions. With a "people come first approach", helping colleagues implement relevant SAP technology to improve their achievements and also make their lives easier.

EXPERIENCE

SAP Business Analyst

2020 - Ongoing

Carroll

Rock, AR

Little Rock, AR

Carroll is a leading company on the telecommunications market with more than 4,2 million customers.

- Enhanced team productivity (by 25%) by conducting annual research which pinpointed the need for integration of various SAP management products in 30+ departments
- Trained 12+ junior business analysts in understanding and managing SAP S/4 HANA data
- Customized SAP ERP solutions for the Board of Directors: built a database with up-todate information to help with crucial decisions, which resulted in an increase in 2021 profit margins by 14%

SAP Business Process Associate

2015 - 2018

Schmeler

Dallas, TX

Schmeler is a 30-year-old limited company in the printing and packaging field with over 150 employees.

- Prepared 2016 Budget with Variance analysis to prior years, which also reduced LEAN waste by 35%
- Led the successful SAP integrations for 7 partners and 12 new customers, receiving overall positive feedback regarding how "stress-free" and "simple" the whole process
- Supported the company-wide SAP S/4HANA configurations, which improved customer engagement and feedback by 45% and also facilitated the individual account management

Business Analyst Intern

2014 - 2015

Reilly Group

Atherton, CA

Reilly Group is the global leader in cloud-based sales, marketing, learning, and customer experience solutions.

- Analyzed 2014 and 2015 expenses reports and suggested cost-effective solutions, that increased annual profit margins by 15%
- Assisted 3 senior business analysts in collecting and systematizing information within SAP Business One to ensure all data is 100 correct
- Participated in a full-cycle project management: from drafting proposal and strategizing to implementing solutions to cut back on the new customer onboarding time by an AVG of 2 hours

SKILLS

SAP BI Platform · SAP S/4HANA ·

SAP ERP · Business Intelligence ·

Data Analysis · Meticulous

EDUCATION

BS in Business Analytics

Menlo College

2011 - 2015

Atherton, CA

STRENGTHS

Prioritizing Business Needs

Using SAP BI tool to analyze data and set achievable goals to optimize current systems, which always impacts profit margins by at least 12%.

Systematic Documentation

Up-to-date with the latest national and local compliance regulations to assure that all data is managed and maintained with 100% precision.

"People come first"

Ability to simplify and explain complex technological processes to various departments, so that they understand the range of available SAP solutions. Recognized as "most helpful" and "team player" by 100+colleagues.

PASSIONS

 Innovations and Manufacturing: 2020 Mos Promising Project

> My award-winning project mapped out how SAP S/4HANA tools could be used to cut back waste and ensure processes were eco-friendly

Travel and photography

Ardent traveller, in the past 5 years have visited 29 countries in 3 continents and counting...